RAHI PATEL

SUMMARY

Experienced Android Developer with 2+ years of expertise designing, developing, and maintaining native and hybrid Android apps. Collaborates effectively, leading architecture and design from conception to launch. Proven in enhancing engineering processes and tools to boost team effectiveness within agile development environments.

EXPERIENCE

Bhavi Technologies Pvt.Ltd, Vadodara, India - Junior Android Developer

08/2020 - 08/2021

- Implemented software development Life cycle, Skills, and front-end/back-end to develop Android applications using version control software.
- Demonstrated proficiency in MVVM and Architecture Components to design scalable and maintainable application architectures.
- Developed several Android mobile applications like Quick-Expunge, Cozicare, and Recyclopedia using object-oriented design for JAVA and Kotlin.
- Utilized Android SDK to create intuitive user interfaces following design patterns and best practices.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to facilitate communication between Android applications and backend services.
- Optimized applications which resulted in a 40% increase in performance.

Friendly IT Solution, Vadodara, India - Android Developer Co-op

09/2017 - 07/2018

- Gained experience in the fundamentals of Java with Android development.
- Worked with several databases and Cloud platforms.
- Stayed abreast of current technological trends, developments, and best practices in information security, wireless network architecture, and mobile technologies to inform decision-making and solution design.
- Implemented a WebRTC project which included IOT and Android programming.

SKILLS

- Languages: JAVA, KOTLIN, C# fundamentals, HTML & CSS, XML.
- Libraries: Retrofit, OKHTTP, RxJava, Dagger, Firebase, Firestore, SQLite, Glide, Databinding, CamView, Volley, Espresso, Junit, Material UI, SQL, JSON to GSON.
- Software: Android Studio, Postman, Git version control, Bitbucket, Visual Studio, Microsoft Office.

EDUCATION

Mobile Solutions Development | Conestoga College - GPA: 3.6/4 (Waterloo, ON)

09/2021 - 12/2022

B.Engg, Computer Engineering | Gujarat Technological University - (Ahmedabad, India)

06/2016 - 05/2020

PROJECTS

Smart Paper Keyboard / Final Year Project (Android and IoT)

- A portable Keyboard designed and developed to save space and quality where a user can draw his layout capturing his fingers in real time and writing that into an android Application.
- Generated Responses to the Android app within 2 seconds with the help of web protocols using Raspberry Pi and Firebase.

Batech App / Android-Project (Client Project)

- Implemented a paperless solution to replace traditional paperwork for maintenance forms.
- Created a user-friendly interface for maintenance users to fill out maintenance forms, providing detailed specifications of machines.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Modern Android Architectures in JAVA-Android.
- Android Boot-camping by Udemy.
- Best Research Paper by IJSRSET.